Connor Douglas

+1 (860) 917-3566 | cpd8405@stern.nyu.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/cpdouglas/

U.S. Citizen

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests broadly lie at the intersection of machine learning and economics. Specifically, I am interested in data-driven decision-making and the emergent outcomes of algorithmic decision-makers in economic environments, often studying techniques from reinforcement learning. I am currently pursuing streams in algorithmic pricing collusion along with personalization and adaptation of generative AI content.

Keywords: machine learning, reinforcement learning, data-driven decision making, personalization, pricing, markets, multi-agent systems

EDUCATION

New York University, Stern School of Business2022 - PresentPh.D. Information Systems — Technology, Operations, & Statistics departmentNew York, NYWashington University in St. Louis2018 - 2022B.S. Computer Science & Economics — McKelvey School of EngineeringSt. Louis, MO

• Grade: 3.98/4.0, Summa Cum Laude

• Minor: Design

Professional Experience

United Nations

Nov. 2023 – May 2024

Research Fellow

New York, NY

Adressing mis/disinformation in peacekeeping

- Constructed novel method of coordinated behavior detection through semantic similarity and time differentials
- Studied methods for identifying mis/disinformation
- Built semantic search and clustering functionality in monitoring tool

Washington University in St. Louis, McKelvey School of Engineering

May 2021 - May 2022

Research Assistant

St. Louis, MO

- Advisor: Yevgeniy Vorobeychik
- Devised and constructed solution techniques for an adversarial model of baseball at-bat in order to optimize pitching strategy

Genentech May 2020 - May 2021

Software Engineering Intern

South San Francisco, CA

- Developed novel technique for creating structured data from unstructured clinical trial protocols
- Led project in developing full-stack clinical study management tool
- Designed and built front-end of question-answering tool ingesting protocol documents

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Intro. to Analytics and AI (Graduate)

Summer 2024

Teaching Fellow

New York University — Stern School of Business

Data Science for Business (Graduate)

Spring 2024

Teaching Fellow

New York University — Stern School of Business

Intro. to Econometrics (Undergraduate)

Spring 2022

Teaching Assistant

Washington University in St. Louis — Economics Department

Data Structures & Algorithms (Undergraduate)

Fall 2019, Spring 2020

Teaching Assistant

Washington University in St. Louis — Computer Science Department

Institutional Service

ISPOC 2024

Associate Organizer

Tau Beta Pi (WUSTL Chapter) 2021-2022

President

Engineers Without Borders (WUSTL Chapter) 2019-2021

Treasurer

PUBLICATIONS

Computing an Optimal Strategy in a Baseball At-bat

Connor Douglas, Everett Witt, Mia Bendy, Yevgeniy Vorobeychik *Proceedings of FLAIRS-36 Conference*. 2023.

Techniques for Abstraction of Unstructured Clinical Trial Health Data

Lukas Corey*, Jennifer Crawford*, Connor Douglas*, Benjamin Fernandez* U.S. Patent Office Filing (PCT/US22/30369). 2022.

*Equal Contributions

0.5. 1 well Office I willy (1 01/0522/50005).

Presentations and Invited Talks

FLAIRS-36 Conference: Oral presentation on "Computing an Optimal Strategy in a Baseball At-bat." 2023.

Grants and Awards

NSF GRFP: Award won in Economics (2024); Total Funding: \$159,000

National Merit Scholarship: Scholarship awarded by Pfizer (2018); Total Funding: \$12,000